Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com · antoine.soetewey@uclouvain.be

Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical methods applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level, at UCLouvain as teaching assistant and at UNamur as invited lecturer. I also provide trainings and consulting in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service (SMCS).

Education

2024	PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2016	MSc in econometrics – Maastricht University, Netherlands
2015	MSc in economics – KULeuven, Belgium

Research experience

2017 – Present **Doctoral researcher** in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium

- Thesis: Waiting period from diagnosis for mortgage insurance issued to cancer survivors (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit)
- All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research

Teaching experience

2017 – Present **Teaching assistant and visiting lecturer** in statistics – UCLouvain & UNamur, Belgium

- See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching

2018 – Present Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates in statistics – SMCS, Belgium

Industry experience

2018 - Present

Consultant in statistics and data analysis for:

- Researchers and academics SMCS, Belgium
- Professionals and companies datanalyze.be

2016 - 2017

Data scientist - Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

Technical skills & languages

Software

- R (RStudio, R Markdown & Quarto, R Shiny), Jamovi, GitHub/GitLab, LATEX
- Web development

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)